Aaron Fritz Santos

Web Developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/afsaints0987/

Marikina City, PH, 1803

+63 995 861 3015

www.saintsdev.com/fritzsantos

saints0987@gmail.com

Summary

As a solution-driven web developer and web designer with 2 years of experience creating business solutions for SMEs, I look forward to sharing my technical and analytical skills with any organization I'll be working with.

In my role as a Web Developer, I create and maintain websites using technologies such as JavaScript (ReactJS, VanillaJS), SASS and Bootstrap, and WordPress. As for my Web Designer role I design websites using Figma and Adobe Photoshop and Adobe XD.

I am a team player, and handling a team and working in a team is one of my strengths. I manage my time wisely as I can work fast. I have a positive attitude towards work and am also eager to learn new skills.

With more than 10 years of experience in customer service specifically in the aviation industry, I consider myself to have good interpersonal and problem-solving skills as well as decision-making, I can do multi-task work with minimal supervision and can work under pressure.

Experience



Jr. Web Developer

Entain

6th Floor Tower 3, Double Dragon Plaza, 1300 Pasay City - Philippines.

Oct 2021 - Present

- Performing general website updates including text and image changes, adding/editing/deleting content
- Scheduling and publishing pages and content according to business needs, marketing campaigns and project briefs
- Quality checking e.g., cross browser testing, comparing design draft against final product, making sure all page's match, and all content in the correct place
- User testing of websites to make sure all links, images and content are
- Ensuring that sites are coded in line with best practices (including W3C etc.)
- Understanding of search engine optimization techniques ensuring that pages are optimized for on-page SEO (Search Engine Optimization)
- Creating web pages to a "mobile first" methodology and ensuring all web pages display correctly across all platforms
- Managing and assisting with the development of all content management systems used by Wave agency
- Proactively identifying and driving forward site improvements, developments, and fixes
- Working with the Brand, Editorial, and Design teams providing development skills to help implement innovative web and mobile designs

Freelance Web Developer

Jun 2020 - Present

- Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Node JS, and Express
- Experience with Python, C#, and PHP
- Strong understanding of web development principles and best practices
- Experience in creating and maintaining websites
- Strong debugging and troubleshooting skills
- · Familiarity with industry trends and new technologies



Customer Service Officer

dnata Singapore

50 Airport Blvd., Singapore Changi Airport, Singapore 819658

Oct 2014 - Jun 2020

Part of the Emirates Group, dnata is one of the world's largest air services providers offering ground handling, cargo, travel, and flight catering services across five continents. I was assigned at Customer Service Department doing the following:

- Handling flights for Emirates Airline and Myanmar Airways Int'l.
- Working as a Flight Controller doing daily report, coordinating with other department (Catering services, Baggage Services, Load Control)
- Supervising at least 10 people in the team and doing daily briefing for the day's flight.
- Reporting to our immediate supervisor/ duty manager in regards about incidents and other things happen on the flight.



Customer Service Assistant dnata Singapore

50 Airport Blvd., Singapore Changi Airport, Singapore 819658

Nov 2011 - Oct 2014

Part of the Emirates Group, dnata is one of the world's largest air services providers offering ground handling, cargo, travel, and flight catering services across five continents. I was assigned at Customer Service Department doing the following:

- Responsible for providing customer service to passengers on various airlines
- Performs ground handling duties during check-in, departure, and arrival
- Works as a lounge staff to assist premium passengers such as first class, business class, and frequent flyer customers
- Handles VIPs on various airlines



Customer Service Agent

Philippine Airport Ground Support Solutions Inc.

Pair-Pags Center, 2nd Floor,, Ninoy Aquino Ave, Pasay, Metro Manila

Jul 2008 - Oct 2011

- Performing ground handling tasks such as check-in, departure, and arrival services
- Handling baggage cases related to missing, pilferage and damaged baggage
- Managing flights for EVA Airways.

Education



University of Santo Tomas

Jun 2004 to Mar 2008

Bachelor of Science Major in



National College of Business and Arts

Jun 2000 to Apr 2004

High School Diploma

Graduate

Skills

- Full Stack Web Development
- UI/UX Design
- Graphic Design
- Customer Service Operations
- Social Media Management
- Airline Service Mgmt.

Certification

Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp.org

Apr 4, 2021

React.JS Essential Training

LinkedIn Learning

Mar 10, 2022

Introduction to Programming using Python

Department of Information and Communication Technology

Nov 29, 2022

Programming for Intermediate Users using Python

Department of Information and Communication Technology

Dec 2, 2022

Learning Next JS

LinkedIn Learning

Jan 6, 2023